<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gbl08ma</title>
    <link>https://gbl08ma.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on gbl08ma</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gbl08ma.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>UnderLX</title>
      <link>https://gbl08ma.github.io/projects/underlx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gbl08ma.github.io/projects/underlx/</guid>
      <description>Go to the Google Play page
GitHub repo
An unofficial Android app for the Lisbon Metro. The long-term goal is to become the only Lisbon Metro app users will ever need, and perhaps most importantly, the one they&amp;rsquo;ll want to have. This app introduces a number of features not usually seen on transit apps, such as real-time location, service quality indicators, and a strong collaborative component.
In a symbiotic relationship with the app, I also built the &amp;ldquo;Perturbações&amp;rdquo; (&amp;ldquo;Disturbances&amp;rdquo;) website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clouttery</title>
      <link>https://gbl08ma.github.io/projects/clouttery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gbl08ma.github.io/projects/clouttery/</guid>
      <description>Go to the website
A battery monitoring web service. It lets you see the battery history for all of your devices in one place, and you can get notifications about the batteries. Using Go, C#, Java and Python, I built a custom backend and website, clients for Windows, Android and Linux, and even a billing system&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s one of those ambitious projects that always feels 10% done. So many ideas, so little time&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eigenmath</title>
      <link>https://gbl08ma.github.io/projects/eigenmath/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gbl08ma.github.io/projects/eigenmath/</guid>
      <description>See on GitHub | Discussion thread at Cemetech
A port of the Eigenmath symbolic math engine to the fx-CG 10&amp;frasl;20 calculators.
I built all of the UI, which is a console with many bells and whistles to make it usable on the calculator&amp;rsquo;s keyboard and screen. I also had to dive in the internals of the engine to fix some bugs, optimize the memory usage and implement expression pretty-printing and function graphing (it&amp;rsquo;s a graphic calc, after all!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Viewer</title>
      <link>https://gbl08ma.github.io/projects/imageviewer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gbl08ma.github.io/projects/imageviewer/</guid>
      <description>See on GitHub | Discussion thread at Cemetech
An image viewer for the fx-CG 10&amp;frasl;20 calculators.
I took libpng and ChaN&amp;rsquo;s JPEG decoding library, made small tweaks so things were a bit faster on the calculator&amp;rsquo;s limited CPU and memory, and designed an appropriate user interface. I didn&amp;rsquo;t write much code and it&amp;rsquo;s nothing particularly novel, however, of my add-ins, this is probably the most popular one in online calculator communities - sometimes, the simplest things are enough to satisfy the needs of the users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://gbl08ma.github.io/projects/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gbl08ma.github.io/projects/projects/</guid>
      <description>Some of my projects are unoriginal, others are original but not very useful, and a big number of them never get to be more than good intentions. Some of my ideas are so ambitious that I never find enough time or motivation to work on them. Sometimes, the problem they were trying to solve ends up not being a problem at all, or at some point I find out someone came up with a much better solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Utilities</title>
      <link>https://gbl08ma.github.io/projects/utilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gbl08ma.github.io/projects/utilities/</guid>
      <description>See on GitHub | Discussion thread at Cemetech
An add-in for the Casio fx-CG 10&amp;frasl;20 calculators that provides many tools, including:
 a complete file manager, with file search, clipboard, compression (using the heatshrink lib)&amp;hellip; text editor image viewer (JPEG only, see also the complete, standalone version) calendar (with events, event search, month, week and day views&amp;hellip;) chronometer  &amp;hellip;and much more. I even glued in a scripting engine (PicoC, not my creation) so that other people could use my own UI toolkit and helper functions, combining all of the code contained in Utilities as they please.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tny.im shortener</title>
      <link>https://gbl08ma.github.io/projects/tnyim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gbl08ma.github.io/projects/tnyim/</guid>
      <description>Go to the website
A website that takes URLs, email addresses, lists of links, text snippets, etc. and gives a short URL for them. It&amp;rsquo;s based on YOURLS, but I build a huge shell around it, with everything that makes it more than a URL shortener. No plans to open-source it - it&amp;rsquo;s a giant mess of PHP code which I only touch for security fixes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://gbl08ma.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gbl08ma.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>gbl08ma is the awkward username that I, a 20 years old guy called Gabriel Maia, have been using on the internet for the last ten years. So despite not using social networks very much if at all, I&amp;rsquo;m extremely traceable - go ahead and Google me.
I&amp;rsquo;m a software developer: I build websites, desktop apps, Android apps, embedded software for things like the ESP8266 and graphical calculators, and more. I have been doing this for the last&amp;hellip; five years?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://gbl08ma.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gbl08ma.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t bite.
You can reach me at one of my email addresses:
 gabriel at tny.im gbl08ma at gmail.com  &amp;hellip;or through matrix.org: @gbl08ma:matrix.org
&amp;hellip;or in 140 characters or less: https://twitter.com/gbl08ma
&amp;hellip;or through Telegram: search for gbl08ma
&amp;hellip;or through Discord: gbl08ma#3988
&amp;hellip;or through Skype: search for gbl08ma
If somehow everything else fails and you have a contact form fetish, I have got you covered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>https://gbl08ma.github.io/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gbl08ma.github.io/home/</guid>
      <description>Hey there! I&amp;rsquo;m a software developer: I build websites, desktop apps, Android apps, embedded software for things like the ESP8266 and graphical calculators, and more.
This website is where I list the stuff I work on and that may not be on my GitHub profile. I also have a blog where, once in a blue moon, I uninspiredly write uninspiring posts and rants about either stuff I&amp;rsquo;m working on, or things that are happening.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>